{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The evolutionary record suggests that the first occurrence of multicellularity was in the kingdom", "opta": "Monera", "optb": "Protista", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "Plantae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of sets of chromosomes in a dikaryotic cell", "opta": "is greater than diploid cell", "optb": "is lesser than diploid cell", "optc": "is equal to diploid cell", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slime molds differ from the moldy fungi", "opta": "in their mode of nutrition: phagocytosis for the slime molds; absorptive heterotroph for moldy fungi", "optb": "in that the moldy fungi produce amoeboid or flagellated cells and the slime molds do not", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which spore is on a club and results from the fusion of two nuclei from different strains of the same fungi?", "opta": "Ascospore", "optb": "Basidiospore", "optc": "Blastospore", "optd": "Conidiospore", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bread mold Rhizopus stolonifer belongs to which of the following fungal divisions?", "opta": "Ascomycota", "optb": "Deuteromycota", "optc": "Oomycota", "optd": "Zygomycota", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Saprophytic fungi", "opta": "engulf their food in order to break it down.", "optb": "secure their food from dead organic materials", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fruiting body of a mushroom is called", "opta": "sorocarps", "optb": "basidiocarps", "optc": "ascocarps", "optd": "plasmodiocarps", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of phagocytosis done by the Plasmodium", "opta": "is greater than by the water mold mycelium", "optb": "is lesser than by the water mold mycelium", "optc": "is equal to by the water mold mycelium", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water molds belong to which division?", "opta": "Ascomycota", "optb": "Basidiomycota", "optc": "Chytridiomycota", "optd": "Oomycota", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ produce basidiospores.", "opta": "Slime molds", "optb": "Dimorphic fungi", "optc": "Club fungi", "optd": "Sac fungi", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these spores are characteristic of the black bread mold Rhizopus?", "opta": "Arthrospore and Ascospore", "optb": "Ascospore and Zygospore", "optc": "Arthrospore and Blastospore", "optd": "Sporangiospore and Zygospore", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "All members of Sac fungus are also members of chemo-lithotrophic autotroph, but not all members of chemolithotrophic autotroph are members of Sac fungus.", "optb": "All members of chemolithotrophic autotroph are also members of Sac fungus, but not all members of Sac fungus are members of chemolithotrophic autotroph.", "optc": "All members of Sac fungus are members of chemolithotrophic autotroph, and all members of chemolithotrophic autotroph are members of Sac fungus.", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following does not represent a human disease caused by fungi?", "opta": "Ringworm", "optb": "Cryptococcosis", "optc": "Malaria", "optd": "Jock itch", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi that lack partitions (septa) are called", "opta": "ahyphae", "optb": "coenocytic", "optc": "yeast", "optd": "conidia", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the statement that does not apply to the kingdom Fungi", "opta": "The fungi are eukaryotic, multicellular, ingestive heterotrophs", "optb": "Some fungi form beneficial interrelationships with plants", "optc": "The fungal life cycle typically includes a spore stage", "optd": "Certain fungi are natural sources of antibiotic substances", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of peptidoglycan in the cell walls of a mushroom", "opta": "is greater than the amount of chitin in the cell walls of a mushroom", "optb": "is lesser than the amount of chitin in the cell walls of a mushroom", "optc": "is exactly or approximately equal to the amount of chitin in the cell walls of a mushroom", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi are important to food webs because", "opta": "they are photoautotrophs", "optb": "they have prokaryotic cell structure", "optc": "they serve as key decomposers of dead organic matter", "optd": "they generate antibiotics that kill competing plants and animals", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ exhibit yeast-like growth at human body temperatures and mold-like growth at room temperature.", "opta": "Dimorphic fungi", "optb": "Black bread molds", "optc": "Sac fungi", "optd": "Water molds", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ produce motile sexual and asexual spores.", "opta": "Slime molds", "optb": "Dimorphic fungi", "optc": "Club fungi", "optd": "Water molds", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi", "opta": "are photosynthetic", "optb": "are prokaryotic cells", "optc": "have cell walls of peptidoglycan", "optd": "secrete extracellular enzymes to breakdown nutrients", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fungus responsible for ergotism belongs to which of the following fungal divisions?", "opta": "Deuteromycota", "optb": "Oomycota", "optc": "Zygomycota", "optd": "Ascomycota", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi in the division Deuteromycota are characterized by the fact that", "opta": "they only reproduce sexually", "optb": "they form sexual spores called deuterospores", "optc": "they are incapable of sexual reproduction", "optd": "a method of sexual reproduction has not been identified", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why are slime molds considered to resemble plants?", "opta": "They can photosynthesize", "optb": "They have cell walls composed largely of cellulose", "optc": "They form a threadlike structure", "optd": "They form structures that resemble leaves", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most significant reason why fungi are not in the kingdom Plantae is that fungi", "opta": "are chemoorganotrophic heterotrophs", "optb": "have unicellular and multi-cellular forms", "optc": "are prokaryotes", "optd": "are eukaryotes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ produce ascospores in an ascus.", "opta": "Slime molds", "optb": "Dimorphic fungi", "optc": "Club fungi", "optd": "Sac fungi", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ecologically fungi are important because", "opta": "they act as decomposers and aid in nutrient cycling", "optb": "they are a major cause of plant diseases", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basidiomycetes include plant parasites that can cause", "opta": "rust and smut diseases", "optb": "candidiasis", "optc": "ergot disease", "optd": "Dutch elm disease & chestnut blight", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A mutualistic association made up of a fungus and a cyanobacterium is called", "opta": "a saprobe", "optb": "a gamete", "optc": "lichen", "optd": "dimorphic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thallus of a mold consists of", "opta": "mycelium", "optb": "spores", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ produce zygospores.", "opta": "Slime molds", "optb": "Dimorphic fungi", "optc": "Club fungi", "optd": "Black bread molds", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are the sexual spore?", "opta": "Ascospores", "optb": "Basidiospores", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mushrooms are classified in which of the following division?", "opta": "Ascomycota", "optb": "Basidiomycota", "optc": "Zygomycota", "optd": "Deuteromycota", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Name the asexual spore(s)?", "opta": "Conidia", "optb": "Sporangiospore", "optc": "Arthospores", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water molds form flagellated spores are called", "opta": "dinoflagellates", "optb": "fruiting bodies", "optc": "zoospores", "optd": "trichocysts", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Acrasiomycota differ from the Myxomycota", "opta": "in their mode of nutrition", "optb": "in their cellular organization", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ergotism is responsible for all of the following except", "opta": "hallucinations", "optb": "Irish potato famine", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "gangrene", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Molds are considered as", "opta": "mesophillic", "optb": "psychotropic", "optc": "thermophillic", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yeasts may undergo", "opta": "alcoholic fermentation", "optb": "homolactic fermentation", "optc": "heterolactic fermentation", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi are important in the production of all of the following commercial products except", "opta": "bread", "optb": "beer", "optc": "cheese", "optd": "rubber", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a member of the division Ascomycota?", "opta": "Aspergillus", "optb": "Claviceps", "optc": "Penicillium", "optd": "Rhizopus", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following divisions of fungi produce uniflagellated zoospores?", "opta": "Ascomycota", "optb": "Chytridiomycota", "optc": "Oomycota", "optd": "Zygomycota", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of nuclei per cell in a dikaryotic cell", "opta": "is greater than diploid cell", "optb": "is lesser than diploid cell", "optc": "is equal to diploid cell", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi differ from the other eukaryotic microbes in having", "opta": "flagella", "optb": "ergosterol", "optc": "chloroplasts", "optd": "an undulating membrane", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mycorrhizae are mutualistic associations between fungi and", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "protozoa", "optc": "unicellular green algae", "optd": "vascular plants", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "All members of heterotrophic organisms are also members of fungi, but not all members of fungi are members of heterotrophic organisms", "optb": "All members of fungi are also members of heterotrophic organisms, but not all members of heterotrophic organisms are members of fungi", "optc": "All members of heterotrophic organisms are members of fungi and all members of fungi are members of heterotrophic organisms.", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism that starts out as amoeboid, phagocytic cells and converts to a sluglike pseudoplasmodium that migrates prior to development of a sorocarp belongs to which division?", "opta": "Ascomycota", "optb": "Chytridiomycota", "optc": "Myxomycota", "optd": "Oomycota", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungi are generally not", "opta": "multicellular", "optb": "containing cell walls", "optc": "photosynthetic", "optd": "spore-producing", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The hyphae of mold are", "opta": "submerged", "optb": "aerial", "optc": "vegetative", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The amount of chitin in the cell walls of the Plasmodium", "opta": "is greater than the water mold mycelium", "optb": "is lesser than the water mold mycelium", "optc": "is equal to the water mold mycelium", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following structures would not be associated with fungi?", "opta": "Mitochondria", "optb": "Cell walls", "optc": "Chloroplasts", "optd": "Spores", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Achlorophyllous means", "opta": "leading in chlorophyll", "optb": "lacking chlorophyll", "optc": "unable to use CO2", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An organism in the Deuteromycota has all the following except", "opta": "asexual spores", "optb": "absorptive nutrition", "optc": "ascospores, basidiospores or zygospores", "optd": "a nucleus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anaerobic degradation of proteins brought about by bacteria and fungi give the products like", "opta": "mercaptans and indole", "optb": "H2S", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terms mycelium and hyphae are associated with", "opta": "algae", "optb": "fungi", "optc": "protozoa", "optd": "viruses", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A mycelium describes", "opta": "saclike structure where fungal spores are produced", "optb": "single fungal strand made up of a long chain of cells", "optc": "interwoven mass of numerous hyphae", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Yeast play an important role in the alcohol industry, converting pyruvic acid into carbon dioxide and ethyl alcohol by the process of", "opta": "glycolysis", "optb": "respiration", "optc": "fermentation", "optd": "Krebs cycle", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ascospores located in asci are found in", "opta": "conidiocarps", "optb": "sorocarps", "optc": "ascocarps", "optd": "plasmodiocarps", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}